usual wager?  sure.
还是要赌吗?  嗯
the, uh, loser cleans the shop, right?
输的去打扫工作室对吧?
yeah.  okay.
可以 没问题
counting it in, i'm ready.
倒计时吧 我准备好了
3, 2...
3 2
1.  hey, wait a second.
1  嘿 等一下
here we go.
黑喂狗
oh.
啊欠w
hello?
喂
oh, hi, mom.
啊 嗨 妈呀
ah! no, no. not you. not you.
啊! 刚才不是对你说话
so, it  hold on  hold on.
好的那么  等一下  等一下
mom, it's not really the best time for me to talk.
妈 现在我这里不好讲话
saturday? sure. oh, mom, hold on.
星期六? 可以 喂妈等一下
mom, hold on. mom, i got to go. i got to go.
等一下 我这边还有点事情
okay. i'll talk to you later.
好的等下再和你说
ahh!
啊!
i lost.
是在下输了
you were looking a little distracted there.
你的精力不太集中啊
yeah, but i did pretty good in reverse.
嗯 但我觉得我倒着开还是开得挺不错的
uh, all right.
哦好吧
all right, sir.
好的绅士
time to get your racing gloves on.
该把你的赛车手套戴上了
we have an entire episode that puts the word "dangerous"
我们要花一整集时间来诠释
into the phrase "dangerous driving."
“危险驾驶”中的“危险”是什么
like what?
比如？
well, we've got a hollywood car chase story to tackle,
我们有一个好莱坞驾车流言要着手应对
that driving at high speed through traffic,
在车流中高速倒向行驶
evading your enemies in reverse, is easy.
躲避敌人是很简单的一件事
but first up, we have a story all about
但首先我们还有一样东西要验证
the dangers of driving while talking on your cell phone.
驾驶时打手机
oh, there's a law against that,
有很多法律已明令禁止
at least as far as holding it in your hand.
是因为你用手握住手机才会危险
exactly, but what is the solution
是的 但是如果有人
for someone who wants to talk on their phone?
迫切想要接电话呢？
handsfree?  hello?
比如免提
你好?
yup, but there's a myth that there is no improvement
是的 但是这则流言宣称免提接电话
in safety talking handsfree versus holding on to your phone,
对安全驾驶毫无帮助
that they both distract you just as much.
因为这一样会让你分心
and i think we should test that.
我觉得我们应该测试一下
absolutely.
当然
talking on a handheld phone
用手拿住接电话
leaves a driver both mentally and physically compromised.
会使驾驶员身心俱疲
going handsfree does eliminate half the problem.
免提接电话似乎减半了这样的问题
but with the other half still there,
但是还是有一半没有解决
some say that it's just as dangerous.
于是有的人说这并没有什么卵用
hey! hey! hey!  hey! hey! hey!
to find out, the "mythbusters" crew
为了探寻真相 “流言终结者”剧组
have constructed a classified course
正在构建一个由老司机Dave Storton
designed by drive expert dave storton.
设计的驾驶虚拟场景
so the first section here is a slalom.
第一部分是这样的回转障碍
so that's gonna test their steering ability
这是为了测试司机打电话时
while talking on the phone.
转向的灵活性
right now adam and jamie are being
现在亚当和杰米
deliberately kept in the dark.
还被蒙在鼓里
storton: coming out of the slalom,
出了回转障碍之后
they'll immediately have to get on the brakes
司机要马上刹一下车
for a lowspeed exercise called the offset lane.
降低速度准备驶进“偏位车道”
because any preexisting knowledge of
因为如果司机提前知道了路线
the route could discredit their data.
这将会影响最终的数据
storton: once through that,
过了这里之后
we head over to what's called a tbox.
我们要经过一个T字型的倒车系统
instead, all they know is that
亚当和杰米现在只知道
they must stick to the speed limits
他们要控制自己的速度
and not clip any cones
不要碰到任何锥子
if they're to achieve a perfect score.
如果他们想得满分的话
满分100
right. if you bolt the two together,
“好的 如果你把它们拴在一起
maybe some sticky tape in the middle,
中间加一点胶带
and that should totally  okay. hold on, hold on, hold on.
就应该可以—— 好的 等一下 等一下
i got a thing to do. okay, wait right there.
我还有事要做 就说到这里了”
okay, so while we know that driving in a car
我们已经知道驾驶时
while holding on to a cell phone and talking
拿着手机接电话
is bad  sorry, that wasn't for you.
是不好的 “不是说的你哈”
the myth is that driving handsfree is just as bad,
而流言说驾驶时免提接电话也不好
that there is no difference
免提和拿手机接电话
between handsfull and handsfree.
两者并没有什么区别
and we are just about to test it on the course behind me.
我们即将会在我身后的场子进行验证
i can see it from a distance,
我在这儿能看到它
but that's as close as i'm gonna get
但是我只能离得这么近
because my ignorance of this course is intrinsic to our test.
因为整个测试的核心就是我们都不知道路线
like adam, jamie's also going
和亚当一样
that extra mile to make sure their science is sound.
杰米也被带进了一里开外 确保实验科学
adam's gonna run this test twice,
亚当将会进行两次测试
first, with phone held in his hand,
首先手持手机接电话
and then, secondly, handsfree.
然后免提接电话
方法
then, i'm also gonna run the test twice.
然后我也要测试两次
亚当 手持电话
亚当 免提电话
杰米 手持电话
杰米 免提电话
but i'm gonna do it in the inverse order.
但是顺序会反过来
杰米 手持电话
杰米 免提电话
the idea here is that we're gonna be able to remove
这么做是因为我们会避免
any bias as far as learning,
每次测试后对路况熟悉程度增加
and getting better every time we do the test.
而导致的实验误差
indeed.
是的
and while adam warms up in the test car...
当亚当在测试车辆里进行热身时
breaker, breaker. we got a, uh, 555 on an m.p.b.
呼叫 呼叫 前方路段有可疑车辆
i'll take care of it.
我现在开始跟过去了
jamie sits down in mission control.
杰米则到了控制中心
all right, i've got my questions,
好的 问题已经准备好了
i've got my phone.
电话已就位
we'll see what we can do to mess with adam's world.
我们来看一下怎样来调教亚当
hello, sir.  hello.
你好  你好
with dave riding shotgun to mark adam's moves,
有Dave协助亚当检测亚当驾驶情况
it's time to hold the phone.
是时候开始打电话了
hello.  hello, adam.
你好  你好亚当
i've got my questions ready for you and we're good to go.
我的问题准备好了 我们可以开始了
3, 2, 1, here we go.
3 2 1  开始
okay, so, if you could compete with the olympics,
如果你能参加奥运会
问题类型1：普通对话主要刺激前额叶皮质
what event would you want to be in?
你会参加什么项目?
um, if i can compete in the olympics, i would, uh,
如果我能参加奥运会 我会
hold on a second. there we go.
等一下…好的开始了
hold on, sorry, um, i think i would do the luge
等一下抱歉…好了 我觉得我会滑雪橇
because it requires, i think, the least amount of physical,
因为我觉得滑雪橇最不耗体力
uh, acuity.
不需要太灵敏
okay. that's great.
好的还不错
问题类型2：听觉上的重复叠加主要刺激脑部顶叶
now, uh, i need you to add the first two given numbers
好的 现在我要求你把前两个数字加起来
and then add the next number to the last number given.
再把最后一个数字加到下一个数字后面
okay.
好的
8 and 7.
8加7
um, 8 and 7 equals 15.
8加7等于15
重复叠加
okay, 3.
好的 3
uh, 10.
excellent. okay.
对了 恭喜
问题类型3：反向的口头跟读主要刺激脑部运动前区
for the next test, i'm going to read you a list of words
下一个测试 我将会列出一些词语
and ask you to repeat them in reverse order.
你要反过来把他们重新说一遍
hold on a second.
等一下
now, this is what you might be wondering about the complexity
你有可能现在在想为什么我们
of the questions we are asking each other while driving.
把驾驶时问的问题搞得如此复杂
flamethrower. fire hydrant. water.
喷火枪 灭火器 水
why aren't we just reading "war and peace" over the phone?
我们难道在电话上玩“战争与和平”吗
注：“战争与和平”为2003年Microids发行的一款策略类游戏
water. fire hydrant. flamethrower.
水 灭火器 喷火枪
well, each of our questions falls into a category that
每一类问题都会
activates the cognitive portions of the brain.
激发大脑内不同区域的活动
general knowledge
常识问题
问题类型4：常识类问题主要刺激脑部杏仁核
which country has the longest coastline?
哪个国家有最长的海岸线？
正确答案：加拿大
uh, the longest coastline of any country. china?
最长的海岸线中国吗？
all require the driver to use the part of their brain
这要求司机用大脑的一部分
to listen at the same time as they're trying to use
听电话和回答问题
another part of their brain to drive.
而用大脑的另一部分来驾驶
adam isn't being judged on
亚当回答问题的正误
how well he answers the questions.
并不会对整个实验数据有所影响
add 1 and 7.
1加7
uh, hold on.
等一下
this is...
这真是
10.
it's how well he's driving that's the only metric.
真正的测试标准是他的驾驶情况
oh! whoa, whoa.
哦！啊！
and the answer to that is not very well.
而亚当的驾驶情况并不理想
um, hold on. sorry.
等一下 抱歉
the combination of one hand on the wheel
只有一只手控制方向盘
and a brain that's multitasking into meltdown means that,
加上被问成了一团浆糊的脑子
by the end of the test,
测试最后
adam's flunked with flying colors.
亚当出色地在测试中得了个不及格
满分 100
及格分 80
亚当 73
jamie, i'm done.
杰米 完了
that was awful.
我都没眼看了
well, uh, let's reset and see whether
我们休息一下 来看看
you're still a menace on the next one.
你下一次是否会表现好一点
all right.
好的
okay.
um.
嗯
well, i've completed my first test,
我已经完成了第一次测试
and talking on the phone was absolutely awful.
接电话真的是像噩梦一般
and then, the car stopped working.
然后车又熄火了
so we are actually going to transfer all of the cameras
所以我们要把这里面所有
and microphones from inside this car
大摄像机和小摄像机
to one of our production vehicles.
转移到另一辆车里面
and i'm gonna run the test a second time, handsfree.
然后开始第二次测试 免提通话
i mean, we still consider my first test valid,
我们还在考虑是否因为汽车的不同
just have to do the second one in a different car.
而放弃第一次的实验数据
so, while the team pushes on,
当测试组继续实验时
what else is on the docket?
流言列表里还有什么呢
so driving in reverse. paint me a picture.
倒着开车 给我描述一下吧
well, look, our hero, let's say,
想象一下 一位英雄
is driving down a one way street.
沿着单行道向下行驶
he thinks he's home free,
他本以为可以顺利脱险
but blocking his path is a villain in a car.
但有个坏蛋开车挡了他的路
来自“亡命驾驶”
Ryan Gosling出演
he's got nowhere to go,
他无路可走
so using the only avenue open to him,
他孤注一掷
the hero throws the car into reverse and backs up,
英雄一个神龙摆尾把车倒过来
bobbing and weaving through traffic at high speed
然后以高速穿过车流
to eventually evade his chaser.
然后逃出了这场追逐战
and you wanna know if this is possible.
然后你想验证其是否可行
i totally do.
当然了
we've been trained to drive in a lot of different ways
这些年我们曾被训练已很多种方法开车
over the years, but backwards isn't one of them.
但是还没有人教过我们如何倒着开车
and it involves a lot of different skills,
这包含了许多特殊的技巧
not only driving ability and spatial awareness but also,
不只是驾驶技术和方向感
really, proprioception. yeah, yeah.
还有体感 是的
let's get to driving.  okay.
我们去兜风吧 好的
克洛斯兰丁航空
beautiful day.
风和日丽
wideopen, empty runway.
宽阔的跑道
the conditions are perfect.
完美的测试条件
oh, wait. we need a car.
对了 还差一辆车
you ordered a car? indeed i did, sir.
你带了车过来  是的 先生
perfect timing.
来的真巧
you know, the movies are packed with people who can drive well,
电影里面人们驾驶技术都是一流的
but they would lead you to believe that you could drive
这让你觉得”我也能行“
forward or reverse, however you choose.
正着开 反着开 怎样都行
we are constantly seeing our movie heroes racing away
我们经常看见英雄和坏蛋追逐
from the bad guys, avoiding obstacles,
巧妙地躲避障碍
and driving all over the place with the rear end of the car
随便怎么驾驶都可以
facing the direction that they are actually going.
就连车屁股对着前面开也是可行的
but before trying out any twists or turns...
但是在他们被弄得昏头转向之前
and...that's a quarter mile.
这是四分之一里
the guys first want to know if
他们首先想要了解
cars can even reverse hollywoodfast in real life.
倒着开车真的能像好莱坞里这么快吗
and for that, they're hitting the straightaway.
他们准备在跑道上开始测试
we've set up a course that's measured.
我们已准备好场地 测速计准备好了
and we're gonna test out these cars,
我们会用这辆车来做实验
see how fast they go in forward
看一下它正着能开多快
and compare that to how fast they go in reverse.
与它反着开的速度进行对比
all right, mr. hyneman, are you ready?
好了 杰米 准备好了吗
i'm good to go.
可以了
all right, commence quartermile test
好的 四分之一里测试
in 3, 2, 1...go.
3 2 1 开始
here it comes.
开始了
80 per hour.
80里每小时
it's a good start for their converted cab.
对于这个改造的出租车而言 结果很不错
but how will that speed compare when it's backtofront?
但是这与它倒着开的速度相比又怎样呢
most cars that you're ever gonna run into
你们坐过的大多数车
have only one reverse gear,
都只有一位倒车档
which means that the top speed of your car in reverse
这代表反着开的最大速度
is ultimately limited by the reverse gearing
将会被引擎倒转能力
and the speed at which the engine is turning over.
和引擎倒转时的速度牵制
now, will our car be able to go as fast
我们的车反向驾驶
as they seem to go in the movies?
能和电影中的场景一样吗
that is just what we're about to find out.
这就是我们将要验证的
okay, commence backwards quarter mile in 3, 2, 1...go.
反向驾驶四分之一里测试 3 2 1开始
jamie's off.
杰米开始了
but from the getgo,
但是现在看起来
it's clear that he's less "fast and furious"...
这显然不够”速度与激情“
...and more "driving miss daisy."
更像是“戴茜小姐开车”
but that's because he's using this run to get his eye in.
因为这次驾驶只是他用来试水的而已
31 miles per hour. i think he can do better.
每小时31英里 你可以做得更好的
i think he's got more.
我觉得他应该更快的
yup, it's test two,
现在是第二次测试
where the rubber will meet the road.
一切都准备好了
okay, adam, i'm in place and ready to go in reverse.
我已就位 准备好反向驾驶了
as jamie, this time,
杰米这一次准备
plans to put the pedal to the metal.
将油门一踩到底了
all right, mr. hyneman, in 3, 2, 1...go.
好的 杰米 3 2 1 走
49, 50, 52, 53.
49 50 52 53
54 miles per hour.
每小时54英里
now, that's more like it.
现在这才像话嘛
四分之一里后
最高时速
54.4里/时
reaching freeway speeds is more than a match
这次的速度与好莱坞相比
for a hollywood hero, but it's not all good news.
接近了不少 不过还有不尽人意的地方
the trick with driving at high speed in reverse
现在反向驾驶测试
was to not do very much,
还只是初期阶段
just kind of hold still and try and keep the car
就是握住方向盘 让车辆
in a straight line.
沿着直线行驶
but unfortunately, we're not going to have that option now
但是之后就没有这么简单了
because, now we've got to drive through a slalom in reverse.
我们将要反向驾驶绕过障碍
and that's all about steering.
很考验转向的技术
that's gonna be really hard.
难度程度大大增加
still to come... bye, cop.
接下来…  再见 条子
backup bologna gets a movie makeover.
倒车怪谈呈现在电影中
yeah!
耶！
and...  hello.
还有 你好
...handsfree goes hightech.
免提通话流言走上高科技
ahh!
啊！
is driving at speed in reverse
反向高速行驶
as easy as the movies make out?
真的像电影一样简单吗
well, not if adam's straight line test...
反正在亚当的测试当中弄
coming up fast.
快一点
...is anything to go by.
一点也没有看出来
ahh!
啊！
whoa!
喔啊！
there are a couple reasons that cars are difficult to drive
汽车反向行驶困难
at high speed in reverse.
是由以下几点原因引起的
hey. yeah, you started to lose it at about 50.
你从每小时50英里之后就开始疲软了
yeah, man.
是啊
and the first is that
第一点 这是因为
the steering is not selfcentering.
转向盘不是以自己为中心
if you let go of the wheel of a car going forward
如果你在向前行驶的车辆中
for just a second, it'll tend to selfcorrect
在短暂的时间内松开方向盘 由于内部构造
because of the offset of the wheels.
汽车会自动调整方向
if you're going in reverse, it does the opposite.
如果反向驾驶 调整也将反向
if you let go of that wheel,
如果你松开方向盘
you're gonna go hard to the side,
你将会很难控制方向
and you're gonna do a 180, and that's dangerous.
将会180度大漂移 非常危险
and correct a little too much, you're gonna lose it.
如果调整方向过度 你就没办法开了
the other thing is that it's all about perspective.
还有一点是关于视角
when you're going forwards, with your head in align
当你向前行驶时 你会自己校准
1 向前开
with the steering wheel, driving's really intuitive.
调整方向 非常直观
眼睛注视前面
大脑处理：直观
but in reverse, you're either looking into the mirror
但是反向驾驶 你要么看后视镜
2 后视镜
or over your shoulder,
要么转过身来
3 侧身看
meaning your brain's having to make complex decisions
这意味着你的大脑要进行复杂的选择
镜像图像
大脑处理不熟悉
非正常视角
from a viewpoint that it's just not used to.
来处理一个你不熟悉的环境
and so, when things go wrong,
当稍微出了一点差错时
you're gonna flip the car or something bad.
你会翻车或者闯一些其他的祸
given their struggles on the straightaway,
向跑道发起挑战
today's test looks terrifying.
今天似乎很有杀气
this is what we call the "diving in at the deep end" test.
我们把这个测试称为“一杀到底”
场地障碍
we've got a course that's full of the kind of challenges
我们在场地设有很多障碍
回转障碍
U型调头
快速过弯
急转弯
a hollywood hero has to face, and we're going to see if we can
这些场景好莱坞英雄都会遇到 我们来测试
reverse through it at high speeds without crashing.
能否反向高速行驶而不碰到障碍
[ laughs ] this is why we have insurance.
所以我们才会买保险
it's a course that a movie maestro
这样的测试电影中的老司机
would finish in a flash.
可以轻松加愉快地通过
but how will the mythbusters manage?
但是流言终结者会怎么样呢
all right.
好的
first run in 3, 2, 1...go.
第一圈 3 2 1 开始
adam's off.
亚当开始了
and from the outset, he's ignoring the mirrors...
一开始 亚当无视后视镜
whoa.
oh, there goes a cone.
撞倒了一个锥子
and going with the overtheshoulder technique.
开始使用“侧身看”的战术
ah!
啊！
but it's hardly paying dividends.
但是这并没有得到什么回报
because not only poor steering cripple his cone count...
不只是因为残念的转向技术撞废了很多锥子
ah.
啊
but his slow speed means his time is terrible.
并且极慢的速度意味着他的时间分很难看
how did i do?
结果怎么样
1 minute 7 seconds.
1分07秒
1 minute, 7 seconds?
1分07秒？
i'll tell you what that does. it wreaks havoc on my neck.
我跟你说 我的脖子简直要断了
well, ii had a couple of screwups on that one.
嗯我现在有几个错误
it's very hard to gauge how hard you need to
你很难去判断
hit a turn in reverse
反过来打一个弯
because all of your metrics for reaction,
因为你要在移动的车上
in terms of how the car moves,
做出所有要反应的判断
are way offkilter.
都是能够保持平衡的
it's a far more sensitive device in reverse.
倒着开车需要更加的灵敏
indeed, but can jamie master the method
的确但是吉米是否可以掌握方法
and reverse this myth's fortunes?
并且倒转这个流言?
all right, cowboy.
准备好了吗 牛仔
here we go in 3, 2, 1...go.
嘿喂狗 3 2 1 走你
i love that this is our job.
我喜欢我们的这份工作
unlike adam, jamie's using the mirrors
与亚当不同的是杰米使用的后视镜
and the overtheshoulder system.
加上“侧身看”的战术
but it's not a winning combination...
但是这不是一个成功的战术
because his crash course
因为他的撞击次数
is even worse than adam's.
比亚当的还要糟糕
but eventually, he crawls to the finish line
但是最终他还是开回了终点
in a sluggish 72 seconds...
用了漫长的72秒
...which is not good news for the myth.
这不是流言的好消息
okay, you win.
好吧 你赢了
but all is not lost.
但是还不是结束的时候
look, there is no doubt that this test was hard.
看毫无意义这次的测试很糟糕
ah!
啊！
the course was difficult, and we are at the novice end
这当然是困难的
of the reverse driving spectrum.
我们是倒转开车的新手
but with some expert training,
但是如果我们有专家的培训的话
will we be able to bring this myth back from the brink?
我们能够重新证实这则流言吗?
that's what's next.
这就是我们的下一步
actually, not quite.
实际上不确定
because next, the guys are jumping ship back to alameda
因为接下来两人要跳船回到阿拉米达
to find out if handsfree is as distracting
来测试免提是否会分心
as holding the phone.
像拿着电话一样没用
uh, hello, jamie.
嘿 你好啊 杰米
adam started with a handsfull control...
亚当开始第一次测试的时候
oh, whoa. whoa.
哦 喔哦 我哦
that went so badly...
这真是太糟糕了
right.
是的
his car refused to continue.
他的车罢工了
okay.
好吧
so it's out with the old.
别用这太破车了
all right, dave. let's do it.
好吧杰米 让我们开始吧
and in with the new.
并换了一辆新车
but will going handsfree really be just as bad?
但是免提真的和单手接电话一样糟糕吗?
here we go.
开始吧
why, hello, this is adam.
嗨 你好 这里是亚当
well, hello there, adam. should i start driving?
你好 杰米 我能开始开车了吗?
yes. go ahead.  okay.
是的 开吧
好的
like last time, adam must complete the course
像上次一样亚当必须完成所有路程
while answering questions both easy...
同时要完成容易的问题
okay, on which continent is the sahara desert?
好的撒哈拉沙漠在哪个洲?
the sahara desert is on the african continent.
撒哈拉沙漠在非洲上
and hard.
以及难的问题
if buster walks halfway around a circle
如果终结者绕着给圆走了半圈路
and then turns around and walks halfway back,
然后转身走回一半的路程
is he now back where he started?
他回到他开始的位置了吗?
yes, he is.
是的
no, he's halfway back.
错他还有一半的路程
ah.
额…
okay.
好了
but despite the obvious burden on his brain,
虽然他脑容量有明显的负担
his driving has got better.
他开始开得好了
and although a clipped cone sees him marked down...
虽然他擦到了一个路锥
sorry. i just hit something.
抱歉我刚刚好像撞到了什么
his final score has improved,
他的最后成绩提高了
but was it due to the phone?
但是是因为免提接电话吗?
well, i've completed my handsfree run
酷啊我已经完成了我的免提电话的开车旅程
of our driving course, and i did it a lot better.
同时我开得更好了点
but here's the thing,
但是这件事情
i found taking the questions from jamie just as distracting
我发现吉米的问题只是会分散注意力
as i did the first time.
像我第一次那样
i feel like my better performance on the second test
我在第二次表现的更好
could be chalked up to just understanding the course
可能是因为已经认识了路程
a little bit better.
所以开的更好了
but that's why jamie's gonna start handsfree
这就是吉米打开免提
and then go to handsfull.
然后去第一次尝试
if that is in effect, we should cancel it out
如果这是有效的话
by changing the order that we do the test in.
我们要改变测试的顺序才能证明
that's the theory, anyway.
不管怎样这才是理论
want to see what you can do with it.
我想看看你会怎么做
i'm gonna suck. i can tell you already.
我可以告诉你我会深呼吸
not only will jamie increase their sample size,
吉米不仅可以增加他们的样本量
but by going handsfree first...
但是要通过第一次测试
jamie and i almost never actually speak on the phone.
杰米和我几乎从来没有用过电话联系过
so this actually has a bit of novelty to me.
所以这实际上对我们来说都有点新奇
the guys are trying to eliminate
这些家伙正在努力消除
any courselearning bias.
任何开车过程中的误差
[ line ringing ] this is jamie.
我是杰米
ah, good afternoon, jamie. it's adam.
啊♂  中午好啊  杰米 我是亚当
go ahead and start driving,
走吧开始开车
and i'm going to start asking you some questions.
然后我会问你一些问题
adam starts with a simple icebreaker.
亚当开始用一些简单的问题来破冰
all right, hey, jamie, if you could wake up tomorrow
好的听着杰米如果你明天早上醒来
and gain any single quality or ability,
你会获得任意一种超能力
what would it be and why?
你希望是什么为什么？
um, i could fly.
嗯我希望我会飞
why?
为什么？
but even that proves too much for jamie.
但是杰米有太多想飞去的地方了
well, uh, because then i could go, um...
好的 嗯  因为这样我可以去  嗯
what was the question again?
你能再说一遍问题吗?
why would you like to fly?
你为什么喜欢飞行?
uh, well, because, that would, uh,
额 好的 因为这个世界 额
it would save a lot of gasoline actually.
这样可以节省很多的汽油
and, uh, you know, i could, uh,
同时嗯你知道的我可以…嗯
oh, look at that.
哦 快看
i bumped over a whole bunch of things.
我撞上了那些东西
with no improvement over the rest of the course...
这次路程的其他地方也没有得到改善
i'd like you to add the numbers 4 and 7.
你告诉我4加7等于多少？
let's see. uh, 4 and 7, uh...
让我想想嗯4加7  嗯
uh...
嗯…
ticktock, grandpa.
时间在流动 老爷爷
10  or, no, 11.
10 还是…  不 11
jamie scores the worst result of the day
杰米的成绩是今天最差的了
a disappointing 66.
另人失望的66
that was awesome.
真是棒极了
he starts every answer with, "let's see."
他的回答总是以"让我想想"开头
i'm sure i was doing the same things,
我很确定我也一样
but it's just very enjoyable to listen to someone so distracted.
但是听一个这么走神的人讲话真是非常有趣
a quick reset later,
短暂的重新准备过后
and they're set for the fourth and final run...
他们将迎来第四轮也是最后的一轮测试
hello.
你好
all right. start your driving.
好的 开始驾驶吧
jamie, handsfull.
杰米 手持电话
i'm going to read you a list of words
我将会读一系列的单词给你听
and ask you to repeat them in a reverse order.
然后让你把单词倒过来复述一遍
crash, burn, demolish.
碰撞 燃烧 拆毁
uh, demolish, uh, burn, crash.
嗯拆毁嗯燃烧 碰撞
e.m.t., ambulance, doctor.
救护技术员 救护车 医生
there's quite a narrative implied by these.
这些词好像暗示了个故事
doctor, ambulance, e.m.t.  yes.
医生 救护车 救护技术员 好的
despite having only one hand on the wheel
尽管单手握方向盘而且开车中途换了手接电话
and swapping the phone middrive, jamie scores 72,
杰米得了72分
a fail by some distance, but an improvement nonetheless.
虽然还有很大差距 但也算是个进步了
so, what does this mean for the myth?
所以这对流言来说意味着什么？
okay, now, for this myth to be true,
如果这个流言是真的
jamie's handsfree score had to match his handsfull score.
杰米免提时的分数应该和手持电话时接近
and so did mine.
我的应该也是
but that didn't quite happen.
然而事实并非如此
graphics, help me out.
上图表
you can see that i drove better handsfree,
可以看到我开免提的时候分更高
while jamie drove better handsfull.
但杰米手持接电话的时候分更高
but that data also shows that we both improved on
但数据也显示我们第二次的时候表现更好
our second runs because we had experience of the course.
因为我们已经了解了路线
now, if we remove that bias by averaging jamie's and my data,
现在如果把我和杰米的数据取均值来去除误差
what do we get?
我们得到了什么结论
beautiful, nearidentical scores
漂亮 这两种接电话的方式
for each of the two techniques.
得到了几乎一样的分数
but we are not done yet, for two particular reasons.
但由于两个原因我们还不能就此做结论
one, our course isn't very realworld.
第一 我们的路线并不太接近真实世界
for starters, there's no traffic.
为新手准备 没有车流
second, and perhaps more importantly,
第二 更加重要的是
is jamie's and my driving abilities.
我和杰米的驾驶能力
we have both received tons of training over the years
这些年来我们进行了许多
in lots of different driving techniques.
针对不同驾驶技巧的训练
whoa!
喔！
whoo, yeah!
喔！耶！
we are quite far from your average joes,
我们比普通司机不止高到哪里去了
and that is what we need next.
接下来我们需要的就是这样的普通司机
aah!
啊！！
3, 2, 1...go.
3  2  1 走你！
现在 杰米和我对于倒着开车的入门知识
teaching ourselves the rudiments of driving in reverse.
已经了解得很深入了
but if we're gonna get really good at this,
但是如果我们真的要变得很在行
we're gonna need to get trained by an expert.
我们还是要请老司机指导指导
luckily, we have an expert in reverse tactical driving
幸好我们有一个精通倒着飙车的老司机
right here.
就在这儿
hello, sir. hello.
你好
brian frazer is a trainer
布莱恩·弗雷泽是位于加州这里的
at the emergency vehicle operations course
一个救急车辆操作课程的教练
here in california.
now, we've used him repeatedly over past years,
我们在这些年的节目中
whenever we've had to learn how to deal with a particularly
每当想知道怎么处理特殊的棘手的驾驶情景时
difficult driving situation.
已经请他来过好几次了
and driving at speed in reverse certainly qualifies.
如何倒着高速开车当然也算其中之一了
all right, brian. where do we start?
好的 布莱恩 我们从哪开始
we're going to put barrel here, two barrels here,
我们要在这里放桶 放两个桶
one on each side of the car. all right.
车的每一侧放一个 好的
brian's first job is to ignore the current course...
布莱恩的第一个任务是无视掉现有的路线
right there is good.
放在那里就好
good. good ending point. aw.
好 终点
this is why we can't have nice things.
这就是为什么我们没有好的东西
and set up something way more straightforward...
并且设置好更直接的新路线
all right, that's the course. now what do we do?
好的 这就是我们的路线了
drive it.  okay. let's go.
跑一跑它   好的 走吧
because the technique he's going to teach
因为他要教的技巧
is surprisingly simple.
超级简单
so i'm gonna change my seating position now
我要换换坐姿
a little bit.  okay.
就一点点   好的
i'm going to prop myself up, loosen my seat belt.
我要靠着座椅 放松安全带
turn yourself as far as you can around.
尽可能地转到面向后面
get your body almost in the center of the  of the car.
让身体几乎处在车中央
okay.
好了
i'm gonna steer the car now with one hand.
现在我要单手开车
but this hand will never leave the steering wheel.
但这手一直都不会离开方向盘
not  you're not gonna let the steering wheel
不 你不能让方向盘
shift in your hand to lock.
在你的手上滑动
you're  you're palming the wheel the entire time.
你要时刻抓紧方向盘
i see. okay, cool.
知道了 酷
and believe it or not,
信不信也好
that's apparently all there is to it.
这显然就是所有的诀窍了
3, 2, 1...go.
3  2  1 走
by shifting his body to the center of the car...
把身体移动到车的中央
oh, wow!
卧槽牛逼啊！
and keeping one hand on the wheel at all times...
并且一直单手把着方向盘
wow, i can't believe how fast you're able to do this.
我简直不能相信你能如此快
brian speeds through the course
布莱恩用41迈的速度
at an impressive 41 miles per hour.
驶过了路线
that is amazing.
那太精彩了
so brian just showed me that something i thought was
所以布莱恩向我展示了我认为不可能
impossible is in fact, totally possible.
而实际上完全可能的技巧
so i'm about to give that a shot.
所以我也要来试一下
this is gonna be cool.
这将会变得超酷
like brian, adam slides to the center
像布莱恩一样 亚当也移到了车子中央
to give a viewpoint that's easier to process.
以获得一个更易于操作的视野
oh, look at that.  yeah.
看啊
okay, so. all right. 3, 2, 1...
好的 3 2 1
and like brian, he then nails the course.
像布莱恩一样 亚当也驶过了路线
oh, that's so cool.
噢 酷极了
to check it wasn't just beginner's luck,
为了证明这不是新手的运气
he tries again and goes even faster.
他又试了一次 甚至比上一次更快
awesome.
棒极了
i got to say, this is amazing.
我要说的是 这棒极了
when we got here this morning, i thought adam was gonna be
早上我们来这里的时候 我以为亚当
training for four, five, maybe six hours.
要训练四 五 甚至六个小时
but it's not been like that at all.
然后事实上并非如此
instead, in just 20 minutes,
在20分钟内
he's gone from being pretty average to being pretty great.
他从一般人变成了一个老司机
and it seems to be all down to the central head position,
似乎正是因为头处于中央的位置
which seems to be letting adam's brain process
使得亚当的大脑得以完成
the direction to turn much more accurately.
更精确的转向
so, we're gonna put him back on our original course to see
所以 我们将把他带回原始的路线
how he does now.
看看他现在能开得怎么样
should be interesting.
应该会很有趣
it's the course the guys couldn't crack.
这条是他们原来无法驾驭的路线
so, you ready to put what you learned into practice?
准备好把你学到的付诸实践了吗
i am. in fact, i can't wait to try this course now.
实际上 我已经迫不及待地想要尝试这条路线了
3, 2, 1...go.
3  2  1走
but will his 20 minutes of training
然而他的20分钟的训练
let adam turn it around?
会让亚当的情况变好吗
he's off to a good start.
他的开头很好
turns are a lot smoother this time.
转弯顺畅多了
he's looking really good.
他看起来真的很不错
yeah!
耶！
well, yeah. he's moving pretty quick.
是的 他开得很快
coming in good.
顺利地来到终点了
yeah!
耶！
tell me, tell me, tell me, tell me, tell me, tell me.
告诉我告诉我告诉我告诉我
tell me, tell me how i did.
告诉我做得怎么样
57.25.
57 25
boom! that was cool.
瞬间爆炸 牛逼啊！
it's close to an astounding result.
已经很接近于一个令人惊讶的结果了
with just two minor modifications...
只凭借两个小小的改动
yeah!
棒！
adam's bettered his best by over 15%.
亚当超越了他的最好记录15%以上
all right, guess it's time to bring on the next event.
好的 我想是时候做下一件事了
and what that means is,
那就意味着
it's time for some reallife movie mayhem.
是时候来点现实生活中的混乱了
but first...
但首先
hold the phone...
先手持电话
because, in driving distracted,
因为在接免提电话时
neither adam nor jamie could drive safely
分心的亚当和杰米
while talking handsfree.
都没法安全地驾驶
but now, in a location way more sophisticated...
但现在 在一个更有经验的地方
it's locked.
锁住了
it's time to up the ante.
是时候让流言升级了
jamie and i have realized we need much more controlled,
杰米和我都意识到我们需要更可控
scientific and realistic conditions,
科学 并且更加真实的情景
which is why we've come here to enlist the help of the experts
这就是我们来这里请教这些专家的原因
at the stanford university automotive innovation facility.
在斯坦福大学汽车创新实验室
when we asked for their help in getting more realistic,
当我们寻求他们的帮助以使实验变得更加真实时
they showed us a virtual world. come here.
他们向我们展示了一个虚拟世界 来这边
this is their stateoftheart driving simulator.
这就是他们最新的汽车模拟器
it is awesome.
棒极了
from the front seat of this car,
坐在汽车的前座
you are completely immersed in a world controlled
你完全地沉浸在了一个由计算机控制和设计的世界
and designed by a computer, into which we can add
我们可以向其中加入
all sorts of traffic, pedestrians, obstacles,
各种各样的交通情况 行人 障碍物
and surprises for all of our test subjects, that's right,
并且惊讶于我们的测试对象 没错
many, many test subjects,
好多 好多的测试对象
while we get to the bottom of this myth.
就在我们更深入地验证这个流言的时候
it's a multimillion dollar machine...
这是一台几百万美元的机器
all right, then.
好的 那么
going for a drive in the simulator.
我要在这模拟器中开车了
which jamie can't resist turning up to 11.
这台杰米迫不及待想利用到极致的机器
okay, here we go.
好 我们走起
i'm gonna go the other way. whoa. this is crazy.
我要开去另一条路 噢 这碉堡了
ah...
啊
crazy driving aside,
除去我疯狂的驾驶
this driving simulator is actually very good.
这台驾驶模拟器事实上很棒
yeah, get out of my way.
从我的路中间让开！
the way the screen wraps around,
这屏幕卷起来的方式
the visuals are convincing enough
这令人信服的视觉效果
that you have to remind yourself
你甚至要提醒自己
that this isn't a real driving scenario.
这并非真实的驾驶情景
he's doing, like, 95. interesting.
他好像开到了时速95 有趣
i'll see how he likes this.
我看看他喜不喜欢这个
in fact, it's so good that
事实上  我开始有点晕车
i was starting to get a little carsick.
这非常好
so i think, as far as testing distracted driving,
所以我认为 对于测试分心驾驶
it's as good a simulation as we're going to get.
这是我们能找到的很好的模拟器了
as well as the freeway...
跟漂亮的高速公路一样
there's also a detailed cityscape...
那里同样也有非常细致的城市街景
oh, i guess i better put it in reverse.
我想我最好挂倒档
...so that all driving environments are tested.
以测试所有的驾驶环境
the 30 volunteer drivers
这30名志愿者
will be judged on whether they pay attention
会被检验他们是否能很好的
to the gps instructions...
遵照GPS的指令行动
at the next intersection
在下一个路口
turn left.
左转
...and whether or not they crash.
还有他们是否会撞车
ah!
啊！
but that's not the only data,
但这并非唯一的数据
because drivers will also wear the latest
因为司机和带上最新的
in eyetracking technology.
眼球跟踪装置
this eyetracking system records precisely where and how long
这个眼球跟踪系统精确地记录了
i'm looking at something.
我在看着什么东西以及看了多久了
now, that's gonna give us hard data as to the level of
现在 这个装置数据将给我们准确的呈现
distraction that i'm experiencing while i'm driving.
我们在驾车模拟时 眼睛所看的地方
with eagleeyed jamie all wired up,
当杰米海纳曼连接好仪器后
he's going to be the first data of the day...
他将成为今天的第一个实验数据
all right. calling him now.
好了 是时候约他了
starting after the break.
休息片刻 我们马上回来
hello?
喂
using a phone on the road is bad news,
在开车的时候接电话可不是什么好事
but is going handsfree just as foolish?
但是如果我们像傻■一样使用免提呢？
to find out, the mythbusters have a simulator
为了验证流言流言终结者们做了个模拟
that's second to none...
这是最吼的
i love this thing.
我爱死这个了
all right. calling him now.
好了现在该打给他了
and a hyneman that's got his hands full.
这将会使海纳曼忙不过来
hello?  good morning, mr. hyneman.
哈罗 海纳曼先生早上好
are you ready to start this test?
你准备好开始实验了么
i'm ready.  okay.
我准备好了 没问题
kick the car into drive, start driving,
让车动起来 开始吧
and i'll start asking you some questions.
接下来我将会问你几个问题
the questions are similar to those posed before.
这些问题跟之前出现过的类似
did you play a musical instrument as a child, jamie?
杰米 你是否像熊孩子一样玩过乐器?
yeah, i had aa tuba in the bathroom
是啊 我卧室里有一个A大号呢
right next to the toilet that i would play when i was,
就在厕所旁边 当我用它的时候 我是在
you know, doing number two or something.
你懂得  就是在拉粑粑或者干别的
but what's interesting is that, on the freeway...
然而 真正的好戏在杰米的高速公路模拟上
speed, underwater, camera.
速度  水下  摄像姬
jamie's driving...
杰米的路况
hold on. you know, somebody just pulled in front of me.
等一下 有人在我前面变道了
and answers...
还有杰米的答案
camera, underwater, speed.
摄像姬  水下  速度
are surprisingly solid.
居然出乎意料的准确
in fact, it's only when he hits the streets...
事实上 好戏才刚刚开始 当他
12 and 7.
12+7
that he starts to waver.
然后他就开始反应缓慢了
okay, uh, let's see. uh, 19.
好的 额 我想想 啊 19
with so many distractions,
在如此多的干扰之中
it's no surprise when jamie takes a turn for the worse.
杰米出错也是意料之内了
<i>automated male voice:</i> <i>at the next intersection,</i>
前方 在下一个路口
<i>turn left.</i>
左转
jamie, you have taken a wrong turn,
杰米 你走错了
and that means that the test is over.
这就意味着测试玩完了
you have failed.
你玩脱了
okay.
好吧
with no rest for the wicked,
没有休息
jamie immediately moves on to the handsfree test.
杰米马上投入到了免提测试中去
hello.
喂
what is the longest running race in the olympic games called?
奥林匹克里最长的赛跑项目叫啥？
the longest running race in, uh, in the olympic game is
奥林匹克里最长的赛跑项目叫
called a maradon.
叫麻辣松
a maradon?  maradon.
麻辣松?  麻辣松…
you mean marathon?  yeah.
你是在说马拉松吧?  是的
okay.
好吧
once again, jamie's focused on the freeway
杰米再一次将精力集中于高速路上
but struggles in the city as his brain tries to process
但是城市里的挑战更加困难 因为他的大脑需要去
the traffic and the conversation.
同时处理路况和谈话
the earth is located in what galaxy?
地球在哪一个星系?
uh, the, um...
额 这个 唔
you know, i don't know the answer to that question.
好吧 我母鸡
like last time...
像上次一样
<i>automated male voice:</i> <i>at the next intersection,</i>
前方 在下一个路口
<i>turn left.</i>
左转
jamie doesn't crash,
杰米没有撞车
but he does ignore the gps...
但他忽略了GPS
oh, i'm sorry. i screwed this up.
噢 我的锅 我搞砸了
...meaning he's failed again.
这意味着这次测试也玩完了
well, the long and the short of it is that jamie has done
总之杰米已经
this test twice in our virtual environment,
在虚拟环境中做了两次这个测试
once holding the phone, once handsfree,
一次是手持电话一次是开免提
and he has failed both times.
然而他两次都失败了
it's looking pretty good for this myth,
这似乎对这个流言十分有利
but we are not leaving it here. no, no, no.
但我们还不会止步于此 是的
we're going to funnel a whole bunch of volunteers
我们准备筛选出一群志愿者
through this testing procedure to get some real numbers
通过这套测试程序以得到一些真实的数据
to back up our potential conclusion.
来资瓷我们的猜测性结论
first of the 30 volunteers is tiffany,
蒂芙尼是我们30名志愿者中的第一个
who will be driving handsfull.
她将手持手机开车
the first thing i want to know is what musical instrument
首先我想知道哪件乐器
you played as a child.
你从熊孩子时就开始演奏
none.
并没有
on the freeway, her driving is solid...
在高速公路上她开得挺6
logic questions.
逻辑问题
and her answers are perfect.
她的回答也相当完美
name four days that start with the letter "t."
有哪四天的名字是以字母"T"开头的？
today, tomorrow, tuesday, and thursday.
今天 明天 星期二和星期四
excellent.
漂亮
but moments after hitting the city...
然而当她开进了城市之后
how much dirt is
有多少泥土……
oh, we just ran down a cyclist.
噢！我刚刚撞倒了一个骑单车的人
this test is over.
这测试乙烷
next up is michael.
下一位是迈克尔
hello?
喂
and, handsfree, he's fine on the freeway...
他开着免提电话轻轻松松地开上了高速公路
what is something you have at home that you should throw away,
你家里有没有什么东西是你应该扔的
but you can't?
然而你并不能扔
ah, my old computer.
啊…我的旧电脑
i still have one that got built in, like, '95.
我还有一台大概是…95年生产的旧电脑
but deadly downtown.
然而到了城镇一切都药丸
um, which country
嗯…哪个国家…
oh! ahh.
哦 啊
ii believe that might be the end of our test there,
我觉得这个测试要在这里结束了
michael.
迈克尔
where did that come from?
那些玩意是从那来的？
thank you very much, sir.
非常感谢你
when the next four volunteers
接下来的四个志愿者
also crash and burn...
也同样惨遭失败…
ah!
啊！
it's looking good for the myth.
这真是有观赏性的流言
stop the car and, please, license and registration, ma'am.
请停车出示驾驶执照和汽车登记证 夫人
and although driver seven
虽然第七个老司机
does make it through the course intact...
确实通过了所有的路程
all right, uh, congratulations.
很好 恭喜你
you have successfully completed the test.
你成功的通过了这次测试
nearly all other drivers,
但几乎所有的司机
whatever their phone fashion, either get lost...
接打电话的时候要不就是错过转向
uh, ron, i'm sorry to inform you that you have now missed a turn.
嗯 很遗憾的告诉你你错过了一个弯道
and thus, the test is over.
所以测试结束了
...or worse.
要不就提前转向
oh, we had a crash, didn't we?
噢 有撞车事故了不是吗
undeterred, the guys plow on
亚当和杰米不屈不挠
through two full days of testing.
继续用两天时间测试流言
and when volunteer 30 takes dramatic evasive action...
且所有30个志愿者全部完成回避动作
i suck at this.
我开的太烂了
the guys have all the data they could hope for.
他们获得了他们想要的所有的数据
all right, we have run a lot of volunteers
好的我们有很多的志愿者
through this experiment, and we've got a lot of data
通过了这次的测试且我们也有了足够的数据
to take a look at.
来看一看吧
so it's time to leave this virtual world,
所以是时候离开这个虚拟世界
drive through the real world, back to our shop,
开车回到现实世界回到我们的工作室里
and crunch the numbers.
并计算这些数字
no way. they said that?
没门伙计他们说的吗？
that is hilarious.
这真是搞笑
hold on just a second. what?
等几秒钟什么？
we were waiting for the results on distracted driving.
我们在等待分心驾驶的结果
oh, okay. uh, i got to call you back.
哦好吧嗯我再打电话给你
yes, we have results.
是的我们有结果了
we tested 30 drivers out in stanford, 15 handsfull,
我们测试了30个司机15个手持
15 handsfree.
15个免提
here is the result.
这里是结果
uh, handsfull  one passed,
嗯 手持一人通过
five failed by driving the wrong way, nine failed by crashing.
五人驾驶犯错 九人撞车
hands free one passed, six failed by getting lost,
免提 一人通过 六个人走丢了
and eight failed by crashing.
八人撞车
what's that mean statistically?
这意味着什么呢？
statistically, it means no difference.
在统计上看来这并没有差异
and what about eye tracking?
那么眼动仪追踪呢？
the eye tracker was very interesting.
眼动仪追踪的数据非常的有趣
across all 30 drivers, the amount of time they spent
在所有三十个司机里面他们花费的时间
looking at something other than the road
都在找路上面
was identical between handsfree and handsfull.
手持和免提都是相同的
well, there you have it.
嗯 你说到点子上了
don't use your cell phone while you're driving.
开车时请勿使用手机
yeah, i'm done. okay.
耶 我搞定了 好的
so, where do you want to meet for lunch? absolutely.
我们到哪儿见面去吃午饭？ 当然了
coming right up, the guys rev in reverse...
很快 流言终结者们开始为了一个令人惊讶的结论
yeah!
耶！
for a confounding conclusion.
开起了倒车
ah!
啊
in driving in reverse, there's a problem.
开倒车的时候出了点状况
we  we can't catch a break today.
我们 我们今天不能休息了
we just rolled up the windows
我们刚摇上了车窗
'cause the wind's so diabolical,
今天的风儿好喧嚣啊
and we locked the keys inside.
我们还把钥匙锁在了里面
luckily, for once,
幸运的是这一次
there's a cop around when you need him.
在你需要的时候有一个警察在附近
hey!
嘿！
mythbusters, repossessing cars since 1979.
流言终结者自1979年起专业回收车辆
it's all about reverse driving in this episode,
本集中全都倒车是为了判断好莱坞中
and how easy it is versus how easy hollywood makes it seem.
“我们不用很麻烦很累就能倒车”是否属实
whoa!
哇哦！
jamie and i have tried out some courses ourselves.
杰米和我已经亲自试学过一些课程
we've been trained by a cop who is an expert
我们的教练是一个对于倒车
in driving in reverse.
很在行的警察
here we go. 3, 2...
嘿喂狗 3 2
the reverse.  oh.
倒车 哦
there we go.  thank you.
我们开始吧 谢谢
so now, it's time for me to take all of the skills
现在就是我使尽浑身解数的时候了
i've thus far learned and put them to a real test.
为此我学习了很多并且要付出实践
i'm here at an abandoned neighborhood
我现在在加州玛丽安的一个废弃街区
in marina, california, where my crew has set up a course,
我们的团队已经在此设定了一条路线
and i'm just supposed to drive as fast as i can in reverse.
我只需要尽可能快地倒车
i'm actually pretty curious how this is gonna turn out.
实际上我非常好奇结果会怎样
this final farewell is a half mile of twists and turns.
最后的告别仪式是长达半英里的迂回曲折
but it's got a whole lot more besides...
整个场地远不止这些
as the guys have put the movie mayhem back into this myth.
工作人员已把电影中的混乱场面“倒入”流言
and that's not just the props.
并且那些物品都不是道具
we're gonna put a little pressure on adam,
我们会给亚当施加一点压力
because i'm gonna be in a cop car
因为我会开着一辆警车
on his ass the whole way,
一路尾随他
with the sole exception that, when he sees me and takes off,
唯一的特殊情况下当他看到我并且发动汽车时
i'm gonna be outside my car.
我将在车外
so he's gonna have just a little bit of a head start.
所以它可以在开始领先一点点
adam's goal, like the classic hollywood hero,
亚当的目标  就像经典的好莱坞英雄
is to make it to the finish line before those pesky police.
是比那些讨厌的警察先到终点
that is a cop. that's bad.
卧槽那里有个条子 这真蛋疼
but with reverse gear his only option,
但是倒挡是他唯一的选择
will he escape to victory?
他会逃脱并迎来胜利吗?
here we go. bye, cop.
黑喂狗 再见 条子
the chase is on.
追逐开始了
here we go. gettin' the heck outta here.
黑喂狗 从这见鬼的地方逃出去
and by the time jamie's got going,
同时 杰米正在行动
adam's already out of sight.
亚当早就不见了踪影
make a righthand turn here.
在这里右转弯
don't let go of that wheel.
不要松开车轮
by shifting to the central position,
通过移动到中间位置
he's able to navigate with skill.
他已经能够熟练地转向
whoa. flaming car! dude.
哇 燃烧着的车！ 伙计
oh, man. postapocalypse.
哦 天哪 后启示录世界
at least, when he wants to.
最终 当他想要
i want those boxes. come on. yeah!
我想撞那些纸箱 来吧 耶！
but while his steering is supreme...
但是同时它的操作是最重要的
i don't know where he is. i hope he's not close.
我不知道他在那里 我希望他不要太靠近
his speed, while fast, is no match for jamie.
他的速度  哪怕已经这么快  也赶不上杰米
oh, fruit stand.
哦  水果摊
i'm not gonna miss the fruit stand.
我不会错过这个水果摊的
whoa! aah. oh!
喔哦 嗷 哦
adam may be down, but he's not out,
亚当也许失手了  但他还没出局
as he reverses back uphill...
当他回头去上坡
ah, i'm going still!
啊 我还在开
a strategy that the hyneman then copies.
海纳曼脑中浮现出一种策略
with both drivers now revving in reverse,
两位驾驶员都转过头来
it's a case of who's gonna blink first.
这是关乎谁先眨眼的事情
oh!
哦！
oh.
哦
yet another in the long line of things that we should just
到这时候一大串东西应该
set up for the public and charge money for.
由群众列出并向我们索赔
that was awesome.
棒极了
step out of the car with your hands up.
从车里出来 举起手来
okay.
好吧
that was so much fun.
这真是太有趣了
oh, my god. that was the best thing ever.
哦 我的天 这真是最棒的事情
well, that went pretty much as good as i could have imagined.
好吧  这和我能想象的一样运作完美
first off, the course was amazing,
开始的时候线路很惊人
full of all sorts of really interesting obstacles,
各种各样的有趣的障碍物
from fruit stands to dudes fixing their cars to,
从水果摊到修理车子的伙计
come on, a flaming car.
天啊  还有一辆着火的车
i also was able to go through it really fast, i mean,
我也能够飞快地穿过它 我的意思是
fast enough where i almost lost control of the car on a couple
快到我差点在几条直路
of the straightaways.
直路上上失去控制
like, it started fishtailing.
车头就像鱼扭尾巴
but because of brian's training,
但是因为布莱恩的训练
i was able to bring the car back under control.
我能够重新将车取得控制
oh, oh, almost lost a little control there.
哦 哦 差点失去一点操控
then, i actually spun out when jamie hit me.
然后  杰米撞我的时候我确实打转了
but again, in reverse, i bolted back up the hill.
但是我又一次扭转并上了坡
and jamie chased me, and it was all going pretty good.
然后杰米抓住我了 这一切都进行的很好
but i was going too fast on the accelerator and i spun out.
但是我加速太快了所以我打转了
he jammed into my front wheel, and i could not move.
他卡在我前轮上所以我没法移动
test over.
测试结束
so how do you wanna call it?
那么你怎么觉得呢
i have to say, i started this story
我必须说流言刚开始的时候
thinking it was gonna be handily busted.
我以为绝对是被终结的
and i am now thinking that it's actually plausible,
但是我现在觉得这完全是有可能的
that it's not unreasonable how much speed
不管多少速度和机动性
and maneuverability you can get going in reverse.
你倒转的时候可以拥有
yeah, i mean, both of us, i think,
耶  意思是 我们都认为
if we had our choice would go, you know, front forward, um,
但是如果我能选择的话
'cause that's gonna be your better option.
因为这会是你更好的选择
but it's surprising how good it can be.
但这是多么好 这太惊人了
let's call it plausible. all right.
那我们就认为是有可能了好吧
i'm gonna drive forward home, though.
那么我要往前开回家
if you can.
只要你行